VICTOR S. S. BARROS

AI | Machine Learning Engineer

I have more than 30 years of experience in the Information Technology area. I have extensive experience as a systems analyst, programmer and information systems consultant, working on developments. I have dedicated myself to the area of Machine Learning.

$\succ\!\!<$	vicssb@yahoo.com
	55(12)981328278
in	linkedin.com/in/victor-sergio-silva-barros
Q	SP- Brazil
O	youtube.com/@proftiovictor2104

Languages

- English (Advanced professional)
- Portuguese (Native)

Professional Experience

Full-Stack Developer | Machine Learning Engineer | Data Analyst

SORRAB COMPUTATION, SP- Brazil

July 1997 - Present

- Led teams in the successful delivery of several projects, strong problem-solving skills and ability to work in a collaborative environment, resulting in customer satisfaction.
- Developed and maintained project plans, ensuring timely completion of milestones. Worked as an IT consultant, programmer analyst in C, C#, C++, Delphi IntraWEB and Java J2EE.
- Development of financial administrative systems for companies, a loan control system developed in Java J2EE (Eclipse and JBoss), an academic control system developed in Java J2EE (Eclipse and JBoss), ERP systems
 developed in C# .NET or Delphi and for a real estate company, a property demonstration system (Delphi
 IntraWEB), allowing searches and navigation within buildings, reducing the number of visits.
- Implementation of dashboards for analysis of company data, in order to generate business ideas.

Full-Stack Developer | Machine Learning Engineer and Prompt Engineer

Avanade Brasil, SP-Brazil

August 2022 - April 2024

- Full-Stack C# Developer Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein.
 - Creation of endpoints for access to the SQL database and API integration.
- Machine Learning Engineer and Prompt Engineer Grupo Fleury.
 - Training a Neural Network (Python) to classify exam images and subsequently extract information (ChatGPT).

Tutor

CEDERJ - RJ Science and Distance Learning Center

July 2006 - December 2013

 Tutor of the subjects Architecture and Systems Design 1, Systems Engineering, Programming (Pascal), Language 1 (Delphi), Fundamentals of programming, Design and Development of Algorithms, Data Structures, Construction of WEB pages and Introduction to Computing.

Professor

Unilagos College, UNILAGOS, RJ- Brazil

July 2005 - December 2012

• Professor of Applied Computing, teaching how to research and create a project and present it.

Professor

CEFET CAMPOS, RJ- Brazil

May 2007 - December 2009

• Teacher: Database, Data Structure, Project Analysis, Programming Language - Delphi, Programming Logic, Object-Oriented Programming, Low-Level Programming - Assembly, Visual Basic.

Trainee

LNCC - National Scientific Computing Laboratory, RJ- Brazil

March 2004 - December 2004

• Internship in the development of a scientific system, programmed in C language, to predict slope runoff, using a geographic database run on a computational Grid with WebServices (GridServices).

IT consultant

CORFA - Reserve Officers Club, RJ- Brazil

February 2004 - September 2004

• Development of a system for administrative control responsible for bank control of partners and real estate financing.

Aviation electronics technician

PAMAGL - Galeão Aeronautical Material Park, RJ- Brazil

July 1994 - March 1997

• Electrical metrology technician responsible for metrological test automation (analysis, design, programming and implementation in C language). Responsible for installing (software and hardware) a network of 120 computers.

Education

Higher - Geoprocessing Technology

FATEC - Faculty of Technology, Jacareí - SP

February 2020 - In progress

Master's Degree in Computing - Computer Vision using Geometric Algebra

UFF - Fluminense Federal University, Niterói - RJ

June 2011 - December 2013

Postgraduate - Higher Education Teaching

Unilagos College, UNILAGOS, Araruama - RJ

March 2009 - July 2010

Higher - Degree in Mathematics

UFF - Fluminense Federal University, Niterói - RJ

July 2003 - June 2007

Bachelor of Information Systems

UNIGRANRIO - University of Grande Rio, Silva Jardim - RI

March 2000 - November 2004

Certifications

- 1. DP-900: Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals
- 2. AI-900: Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals
- 3. AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- 4. SC-900: Microsoft Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals
- 5. MS-900: Microsoft 365 Fundamentals
- 6. PL-900: Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals
- 7. MB-910: Microsoft Dynamics 365 Fundamentals (CRM)
- 8. DP-100: Designing and Implementing a Data Science Solution on Azure
- 9. Al-102: Designing and Implementing a Microsoft Azure Al Solution
- 10. PL-100: Microsoft Power Platform App Maker
- 11. PL-300: Microsoft Power BI Data Analyst
- 12. PL-400: Microsoft Power Platform Developer
- 13. PL-600: Microsoft Power Platform Solution Architect

Professional Development

Artificial Intelligence

INPE - National Institute for Space Research, São José dos Campos - SP

March 2000 - July 2022

- Analysis of statistical data from Sentinel 1 and 2 satellites for land cover and land use classification in the Amazon region: This work aims at the exploratory analysis of statistical attributes of Sentinel-1 and Sentinel-2 satellites in order to analyze the possibility of classifying the use and land cover, in a specific region, through a Deep Neural Network (DNN), using Big Data from collection 6 of MapBiomas as a reference parameter, which would allow the monitoring of changes in a shorter period of time.
- Repository and article: https://github.com/vicssb/Artificial-intelligence-in-INPE---2022

Various Bootcamps

Digital Innovation One 2021 - 2024

• Link: https://www.dio.me/users/vicssb

Big Data, Data Science, Data Analysis, Microsoft Power BI and AI

Data Science Academy March 2020 - November 2020

3D Graphics Systems

IMPA -National Institute of Pure and Applied Mathematics Association January 2007 - July 2007

Skills

- Project Management
- Agile & Scrum Methodologies
- Collaborative Environment
- Stakeholder Management
- Team Leadership
- Microsoft Project

- Teach
- Communication
- Problem-Solving

Software Skills

- Python
- Java
- CUDA
- C/C++/C#
- R/MATLAB

- Generative Al
- Amazon Bedrock
- ChatGPT
- Azure OpenAl Studio
- Azure Machine Learning
- SQL
- Power BI
- Object orientation
- Linux
- Computer Vision

Awards & Honors

HONORABLE MENTION IN THE STATE MATHEMATICS OLYMPIAD

IMPA - National Institute of Pure and Applied Mathematics Association

August 1992